Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part II WAG.025.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Immigration, Resettlement and Refugee Aid
  - Subseries IV:A: General Files
    - 3. General Correspondence (filed by letter of the alphabet, and then chronologically)
      - A, 1952 (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - A, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - A, 1954 (Box 105, Folder 7)
      - A, 1955 (Box 105, Folder 8)
      - A, 1956 (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - B, [1947], 1948 (Box 105, Folder 10)
        Microfilm reel#: 305
      - B, Jan 1949-Jun 1949 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - B, Jul 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 105, Folder 12)
      - B, 1950 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      - B, 1951-1952 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      - B, 1953-1954 (Box 105, Folder 15)
      - B, 1955 (Box 105, Folder 16)
      - B, 1956 (Box 105, Folder 17)
      - C, 1947-1948 (Box 105, Folder 18)
      - C, 1949-1950 (Box 105, Folder 19)
      - C, 1951 (Box 105, Folder 20)
      - C, 1952 (Box 105, Folder 21)
      - C, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 22)
      - C, 1954 (Box 105, Folder 23)
      - C, 1955 (Box 105, Folder 24)
      - C, 1956 (Box 105, Folder 25)
      - D, 1947 (Box 106, Folder 1)
        Microfilm reel#: 306
      - D, 1948 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - D, 1949-1950 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - D, 1951 (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - D, 1952 (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - D, 1953 (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - D, 1954-1955 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - D, 1956 (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - E, [1947], 1948 (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - E, 1949-1950 (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - E, 1951 (Box 106, Folder 11)
      - E, 1952 (Box 106, Folder 12)
      - E, 1953 (Box 106, Folder 13)
      - E, 1954-1955 (Box 106, Folder 14)
      - E, 1956 (Box 106, Folder 15)
      - F, [1947], 1948 (Box 106, Folder 16)
      - F, Jan 1949-May 1949 (Box 106, Folder 17)
      - F, Jun 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 106, Folder 18)
      - F, 1950 (Box 106, Folder 19)
        Microfilm reel#: 307
      - F, 1951 (Box 106, Folder 20)
      - F, 1952 (Box 106, Folder 21)
      - F, 1953 (Box 106, Folder 22)
      - F, 1954-1955 (Box 106, Folder 23)
      - F, 1956 (Box 106, Folder 24)
      - G, undated (Box 106, Folder 25)
      - G, [1947], 1948 (Box 106, Folder 26)
      - G, Jan 1949-May 1949 (Box 106, Folder 27)
        Microfilm reel#: 308
      - G, Jun 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 106, Folder 28)
      - G, 1950 (Box 106, Folder 29)
      - G, 1951 (Box 106, Folder 30)
      - G, 1952 (Box 106, Folder 31)
      - G, 1953 (Box 106, Folder 32)
      - G, 1954 (Box 106, Folder 33)
      - G, 1955 (Box 106, Folder 34)
      - G, 1956 (Box 106, Folder 35)
      - H, undated (Box 107, Folder 1)
        Microfilm reel#: 309
      - H, 1947 (Box 107, Folder 2)
      - H, 1948 (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - H, 1949 (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - H, 1950 (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - H, 1951 (Box 107, Folder 6)
      - H, 1952 (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - H, 1953-1954 (Box 107, Folder 8)
      - H, 1955 (Box 107, Folder 9)
      - H, 1956 (Box 107, Folder 10)
      - I, [1947], 1948 (Box 107, Folder 11)
      - I, 1950 (Box 107, Folder 12)
      - I, 1951 (Box 107, Folder 13)
      - I, 1952 (Box 107, Folder 14)
      - I, 1953 (Box 107, Folder 15)
      - I, 1954-1955 (Box 107, Folder 16)
      - I, 1956 (Box 107, Folder 17)
      - J, [1947], 1948 (Box 107, Folder 18)
      - J, 1949 (Box 107, Folder 19)
      - J, 1951 (Box 107, Folder 20)
      - J, 1953 (Box 107, Folder 21)
      - J, 1954-1955 (Box 107, Folder 22)
        Microfilm reel#: 310
      - J, 1956 (Box 107, Folder 23)
      - K, 1947 (Box 107, Folder 24)
      - K, Jan 1948-Apr 1948 (Box 107, Folder 25)
      - K, May 1948-Aug 1948 (Box 107, Folder 26)
      - K, Sep 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 107, Folder 27)
      - K, Jan 1949-May 1949 (Box 107, Folder 28)
      - K, Jun 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 107, Folder 29)
      - K, 1950 (Box 107, Folder 30)
      - K, Jan 1951-May 1951 (Box 107, Folder 31)
        Microfilm reel#: 311
      - K, Jun 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 107, Folder 32)
      - K, 1952 (Box 107, Folder 33)
      - K, Jan 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 107, Folder 34)
      - K, Jul 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 107, Folder 35)
      - K, 1954 (Box 107, Folder 36)
      - K, 1955 (Box 107, Folder 37)
      - K, 1956 (Box 107, Folder 38)
      - L, [1947], 1948 (Box 108, Folder 1)
        Microfilm reel#: 312
      - L, 1949 (Box 108, Folder 2)
      - L, 1950 (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - L, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - L, 1952 (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - L, 1953 (Box 108, Folder 6)
      - L, 1954-1955 (Box 108, Folder 7)
      - L, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 8)
      - M, 1947-1948 (Box 108, Folder 9)
      - M, 1949 (Box 108, Folder 10)
      - M, 1950 (Box 108, Folder 11)
      - M, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 12)
        Microfilm reel#: 313
      - M, 1952 (Box 108, Folder 13)
      - M, 1953 (Box 108, Folder 14)
      - M, 1954 (Box 108, Folder 15)
      - M, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 16)
      - M, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 17)
      - N, [1947], 1948 (Box 108, Folder 18)
      - N, 1949 (Box 108, Folder 19)
      - N, 1950 (Box 108, Folder 20)
      - N, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 21)
      - N, 1952 (Box 108, Folder 22)
      - N, 1953 (Box 108, Folder 23)
      - N, 1954-1955 (Box 108, Folder 24)
      - N, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 25)
      - O, [1947], 1948 (Box 108, Folder 26)
      - O, 1949-1950 (Box 108, Folder 27)
      - O, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 28)
        Microfilm reel#: 314
      - O, 1952 (Box 108, Folder 29)
      - O, 1953 (Box 108, Folder 30)
      - O, 1954 (Box 108, Folder 31)
      - O, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 32)
      - O, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 33)
      - P, [1947], 1948 (Box 108, Folder 34)
      - P, 1948 (Box 108, Folder 35)
      - P, 1949 (Box 108, Folder 36)
      - P, 1949-1950 (Box 108, Folder 37)
      - P, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 38)
      - P, 1952 (Box 108, Folder 39)
      - P, 1953 (Box 108, Folder 40)
      - P, 1954 (Box 108, Folder 41)
      - P, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 42)
      - P, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 43)
      - R, [1947], 1948 (Box 109, Folder 1)
        Microfilm reel#: 315
      - R, 1948 (Box 109, Folder 2)
      - R, Jan 1949-May 1949 (Box 109, Folder 3)
      - R, Jun 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - R, 1950 (Box 109, Folder 5)
      - R, 1951 (Box 109, Folder 6)
      - R, 1952 (Box 109, Folder 7)
      - R, 1953 (Box 109, Folder 8)
        Microfilm reel#: 316
      - R, 1954 (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - R, 1955 (Box 109, Folder 10)
      - R, 1956 (Box 109, Folder 11)
      - S, [1947], Jan 1948-Mar 1948 (Box 109, Folder 12)
      - S, Apr 1948-May 1948 (Box 109, Folder 13)
      - S, Jun 1948-Aug 1948 (Box 109, Folder 14)
      - S, Sep 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 109, Folder 15)
      - S, Jan 1949-Jun 1949 (Box 109, Folder 16)
        Microfilm reel#: 317
      - S, Jul 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 109, Folder 17)
      - S, Jan 1950-Jun 1950 (Box 109, Folder 18)
      - S, Jul 1950-Dec 1950 (Box 109, Folder 19)
      - S, Jan 1951-May 1951 (Box 109, Folder 20)
      - S, Jun 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 109, Folder 21)
      - S, Jan 1952-May 1952 (Box 109, Folder 22)
        Microfilm reel#: 318
      - S, Jun 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 109, Folder 23)
      - S, 1953 (Box 110, Folder 1)
      - S, 1954 (Box 110, Folder 2)
      - S, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 3)
      - S, 1956 (Box 110, Folder 4)
      - T, [1947], 1948 (Box 110, Folder 5)
        Microfilm reel#: 319
      - T, 1949 (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - T, 1950 (Box 110, Folder 7)
      - T, 1951 (Box 110, Folder 8)
      - T, 1952 (Box 110, Folder 9)
      - T, 1953 (Box 110, Folder 10)
      - T, 1954 (Box 110, Folder 11)
      - T, 1956 (Box 110, Folder 12)
      - U, [1947], 1948 (Box 110, Folder 13)
      - U, 1949-1950 (Box 110, Folder 14)
      - U, 1951-1952 (Box 110, Folder 15)
      - U, 1953-1954 (Box 110, Folder 16)
      - U, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 17)
      - U, 1956 (Box 110, Folder 18)
      - V, 1948-1950 (Box 110, Folder 19)
      - V, 1953 (Box 110, Folder 20)
      - W, 1947 (Box 110, Folder 21)
      - W, Jan 1948-May 1948 (Box 110, Folder 22)
      - W, Jun 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 110, Folder 23)
      - W, 1949 (Box 110, Folder 24)
        Microfilm reel#: 320
      - W, 1951 (Box 110, Folder 25)
      - W, 1952 (Box 110, Folder 26)
      - W, 1953 (Box 110, Folder 27)
      - W, 1954 (Box 110, Folder 28)
      - W, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 29)
      - W, 1956 (Box 110, Folder 30)
      - Y, 1948-1953 (Box 110, Folder 31)
      - Z, 1947 (Box 110, Folder 32)
      - Z, 1948 (Box 110, Folder 33)
      - Z, 1949 (Box 110, Folder 34)
      - Z, 1950 (Box 110, Folder 35)
      - Z, 1951 (Box 110, Folder 36)
      - Z, 1952 (Box 110, Folder 37)
      - Z, 1953 (Box 110, Folder 38)
        Microfilm reel#: 321
      - Z, 1954 (Box 110, Folder 39)
      - Z, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 40)
      - Z, 1956 (Box 110, Folder 41)
  - Subseries IV:B: German-Austrian Reparations Files
    - Agreement between West Germany and Israel, Sep 1952 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - American Association of the Victims of Nazism, undated (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, 1952-1953 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Auerbach, Dr. Phillip, 1949-1950 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Axis Victims League, 1949-1955 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Bayerisches Landesentschadigungsamt, 1949-1952 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Committee for Jewish Claims on Austria, 1950-1952 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Committee for Jewish Claims on Austria, 1953 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Committee for Jewish Claims on Austria, 1954-1955 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, Jan 1951-May 1952 (Box 111, Folder 10)
      Microfilm reel#: 322
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, Jun 1952-Sep 1952 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, Oct 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, Jan 1953-Apr 1953 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, May 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, Jan 1954-Apr 1954 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, May 1954-Aug 1954 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, Sep 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, 1955 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims, 1956 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims (Applications), 1953 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims (Applications - Individual) 1950-1956, undated (Box 112, Folder 1)
      Microfilm reel#: 323
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims (Applications - Institutional), 1953 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims (Applications -Institutional), 1954-1955 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims (Applications - Institutional) I., 1956 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Conference on Jewish Material Claims (Applications - Institutional) II., 1956 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - General, 1949 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - General, 1950 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - General, 1956 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Germany, Dec 1953 (Box 112, Folder 9)
      Microfilm reel#: 324
    - Hiller, Jakob, 1954-1956 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Restitution Successor Organization, 1951 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Lists (Interviews), 1949-1950 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Lists (B. Meiksin), 1950 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Lists - Chicago (Indemnification), 1950 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - Lists - Detroit (Indemnification), 1950 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - Lists - New York (Indemnification), 1950 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - Lists - Toronto, Canada (Indemnification), 1950 (Box 112, Folder 17)
    - Lists - Vancouver, Canada (Indemnification), 1950 (Box 112, Folder 18)
    - Negotiations, 1951-1952 (Box 112, Folder 19)
    - Negotiations, 1953-1955 (Box 112, Folder 20)
    - O'Sullivan Committee Report, 1951 (Box 112, Folder 21)
    - Protocols (Luxemburg), 1952 (Box 112, Folder 22)
    - Report on Jewish Heirless Assets in Austria, 1952 (Box 112, Folder 23)
    - Reports/Histories, 1947, 1954 (Box 112, Folder 24)
    - United Restoration Organization, 1952-1954 (Box 112, Folder 25)
    - United Restoration Organization, 1955 (Box 112, Folder 26)
    - Claims: A, undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
      Microfilm reel#: 325
    - Claims: B-Bee, undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Claims: Ber-Bes, undated (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Claims: Bia-Bla, undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Claims: Ble-Bod, undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Claims: Boj-Bre, undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - Claims: Bro-Bru, undated (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - Claims: Buk-Bur, undated (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - Claims: C, undated (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - Claims: D, undated (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - Claims: E, undated (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - Claims: Fa-Fi, undated (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - Claims: Fl, undated (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - Claims: Fo-Fra, undated (Box 113, Folder 14)
      Microfilm reel#: 326
    - Claims: Fre, undated (Box 113, Folder 15)
    - Claims: Fri, undated (Box 113, Folder 16)
    - Claims: Fro-Fru, undated (Box 113, Folder 17)
    - Claims: Ga-Gel, undated (Box 113, Folder 18)
    - Claims: Gen-Gew, undated (Box 113, Folder 19)
    - Claims: Gi-Gl, undated (Box 113, Folder 20)
    - Claims: Go, undated (Box 113, Folder 21)
    - Claims: Gr, undated (Box 113, Folder 22)
    - Claims: Gu, undated (Box 113, Folder 23)
      Microfilm reel#: 327
    - Claims: H, undated (Box 113, Folder 24)
    - Claims: I, undated (Box 113, Folder 25)
    - Claims: J, undated (Box 113, Folder 26)
    - Claims: Ka-Ki, undated (Box 113, Folder 27)
    - Claims: Kl, undated (Box 113, Folder 28)
    - Claims: Ko, undated (Box 113, Folder 29)
    - Claims: Kra-Kre, undated (Box 113, Folder 30)
    - Claims: Kri-Kry, undated (Box 113, Folder 31)
    - Claims: Ku, undated (Box 113, Folder 32)
    - Claims: La, undated (Box 113, Folder 33)
    - Claims: Le, undated (Box 113, Folder 34)
    - Claims: Li, undated (Box 113, Folder 35)
      Microfilm reel#: 328
    - Claims: Lo-Lu, undated (Box 113, Folder 36)
    - Claims: Ma, undated (Box 113, Folder 37)
    - Claims: Me-Mi, undated (Box 113, Folder 38)
    - Claims: Mo-Mu, undated (Box 113, Folder 39)
    - Claims: N, undated (Box 113, Folder 40)
    - Claims: O, undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Claims: Pa-Pl, undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Claims: Po-Pu, undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - Claims: Ra, undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Claims: Re-Ri, undated (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Claims: Ro, undated (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Claims: Ru-Ry, undated (Box 114, Folder 7)
      Microfilm reel#: 329
    - Claims: Sa-Sch, undated (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - Claims: Se-Sl, undated (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Claims: Sm-Sta, undated (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Claims: Ste-Sw, undated (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - Claims: Sym-Szl, undated (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - Claims: Szm-Szy, undated (Box 114, Folder 13)
    - Claims: T, undated (Box 114, Folder 14)
    - Claims: U, undated (Box 114, Folder 15)
    - Claims: V, undated (Box 114, Folder 16)
    - Claims: Wa, undated (Box 114, Folder 17)
    - Claims: We, undated (Box 114, Folder 18)
      Microfilm reel#: 330
    - Claims: Wie-Wol, undated (Box 114, Folder 19)
    - Claims: Wro, undated (Box 114, Folder 20)
    - Claims: Z-Ze, undated (Box 114, Folder 21)
    - Claims: Zl-Zy, undated (Box 114, Folder 22)
  - Subseries IV:C: Child Adoption Program: Correspondence Files
    [Note: Some records in this series date from 1946.]
    - Baltimore, 1946-1948 (Box 114, Folder 23)
    - Baltimore, 1949-1950 (Box 114, Folder 24)
    - Baltimore, 1951-1953 (Box 114, Folder 25)
    - Baltimore, 1954-1955 (Box 114, Folder 26)
    - Baltimore, 1956 (Box 114, Folder 27)
    - Bazaar, 1948 (Box 114, Folder 28)
    - Belgium: General & Lists, 1947, 1953-1956 (Box 114, Folder 29)
    - Belgium: Mila Alter, 1948 (Box 114, Folder 30)
    - Belgium: Mila Alter, 1952-1953 (Box 114, Folder 31)
    - Belgium: Poale Zion, 1947 (Box 114, Folder 32)
    - Canada, 1951 (Box 114, Folder 33)
    - Chapman Dress Co., 1947-1952 (Box 114, Folder 34)
    - Chicago, 1947-1948 (Box 114, Folder 35)
      Microfilm reel#: 331
    - Chicago, 1954-1955 (Box 114, Folder 36)
    - Chicago, 1956 (Box 114, Folder 37)
    - Cleveland, 1948-1955 (Box 114, Folder 38)
    - Contribution Lists (Radio), 1948 (Box 114, Folder 39)
    - Contribution Lists (Radio), 1949 (Box 114, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: General, 1946-1947 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: General, Jan 1948-Jun 1948 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: General, Jul 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: General, 1949-1955 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Lichtenstein, Z., 1949-1950 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Lichtenstein, Z., 1951-1956 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Lichtenstein, Z., 1955-1956 (Box 115, Folder 7)
      Microfilm reel#: 332
    - (Midwest Tour), 1955-1956 (Box 115, Folder --)
    - Correspondents' Service for European Jewish Children, 1947-1948 (Box 115, Folder 8)
    - CYCO: Froyen Centrale, 1948-1956 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Detroit, 1948-1956 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Far Eastern Contributors, 1946-1947 (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - France: General, 1946-1952, 1955 (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - France: Aronson Home, 1947-1952 (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - France: Children's Album (Script), undated (Box 115, Folder 14)
    - France: Colonie Scolaire, 1947-1951 (Box 115, Folder 15)
    - France: Colonie Scolaire, 1952-1953 (Box 115, Folder 16)
    - France: Colonie Scolaire, 1954-1956 (Box 115, Folder 17)
    - France: Lists, 1946 (Box 115, Folder 18)
    - France: Mehring, B., 1947 (Box 115, Folder 19)
    - France: Mehring, B., Jan 1948-Jun 1948 (Box 115, Folder 20)
    - France: Mehring, B., Jul 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 115, Folder 21)
      Microfilm reel#: 333
    - France: Mehring, B., 1949-1952 (Box 115, Folder 22)
    - France: Mehring, B., 1953 (Box 115, Folder 23)
    - France: Mehring, B., 1954 (Box 115, Folder 24)
    - France: Mehring, B., 1955 (Box 115, Folder 25)
    - France: Mehring, B., 1956 (Box 115, Folder 26)
    - France: Mehring, Reports, 1948 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      Microfilm reel#: 334
    - France: Mendelson Home, 1948 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - France: Mendelson Home, 1949-1954 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - France: Mendelson Home (Shipments), 1947-1949 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - France: Ringelblum Home, 1947-1948 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - France: Sigman Home, 1949 (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - France: Vladeck Home, 1946-1947 (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - France: Vladeck Home, 1948 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - France: Vladeck Home, 1949 (Box 116, Folder 9)
      Microfilm reel#: 335
    - France: Vladeck Home, 1952-1956 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - France: Vladeck Home (Mayor Robert Wagner visit), 1955 (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - ILGWU: Cloak Joint Board, 1948-1950 (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - ILGWU: Cloak & Skirt Joint Board, Philadelphia, 1948-1956 (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - ILGWU: Dress Joint Board, Philadelphia, 1948-1956 (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - ILGWU: Eastern Out of Town Dept., 1949-1953 (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - ILGWU: General Staff, 1948 (Box 116, Folder 16)
    - ILGWU: General Staff, 1949-1950 (Box 116, Folder 17)
    - ILGWU: General Staff, 1951-1956 (Box 116, Folder 18)
    - ILGWU: Local 22, 1947-1949 (Box 116, Folder 19)
    - ILGWU: Local 22 (Business Agents' Lists of Shops), 1949-1952 (Box 116, Folder 20)
    - ILGWU: Local 35, 1948-1954 (Box 116, Folder 21)
    - ILGWU: Local 62, 1948-1951 (Box 116, Folder 22)
    - ILGWU: Local 62, 1952-1956 (Box 116, Folder 23)
    - ILGWU: Local 89, 1949-1954 (Box 116, Folder 24)
    - ILGWU: Local 99, 1949-1954 (Box 116, Folder 25)
    - ILGWU: Local 105, 1949-1953 (Box 116, Folder 26)
    - ILGWU: Local 115, 1949 (Box 116, Folder 27)
    - ILGWU: Local 117, 1948-1953 (Box 116, Folder 28)
    - ILGWU: Local 228, 1948 (Box 116, Folder 29)
    - ILGWU: Northeast Dept., 1948-1952 (Box 116, Folder 30)
    - ILGWU: Out of Town Cloak Dept., undated (Box 116, Folder 31)
      Microfilm reel#: 336
    - Israel, 1949-1952 (Box 116, Folder 32)
    - Israel, 1955 (Box 116, Folder 35)
    - Israel, 1956 (Box 116, Folder 36)
    - Italy, 1947-1948 (Box 116, Folder 37)
    - Italy, 1951-1953 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Italy, 1954-1956 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      Microfilm reel#: 337
    - Kansas City, MO, 1955-1956 (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Katzetler Farband, 1950-1955 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Children, 1947-1950 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Los Angeles, 1947-1948 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - Los Angeles, 1949-1950 (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles, 1951-1952 (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles, 1953-1954 (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - Los Angeles, 1955-1956 (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - Montreal, 1947-1951 (Box 117, Folder 11)
      Microfilm reel#: 338
    - Montreal, 1952-1956 (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh, 1948-1956 (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - Poland, 1946-1947 (Box 117, Folder 14)
    - Poland, 1948 (Box 117, Folder 15)
    - Poland, 1949-1956 (Box 117, Folder 16)
    - Poland: Bialystok, 1946 (Box 117, Folder 17)
    - Poland: Dom Dziecka, Bielsko, 1947-1949 (Box 117, Folder 18)
    - Poland: Dom Dziecka, Otwock, 1947-1949 (Box 117, Folder 19)
    - Poland: Dom Dziecka, Srodborow I, 1948 (Box 117, Folder 20)
    - Poland: Dom Dziecka, Srodborow II, 1947-1948 (Box 117, Folder 21)
    - Poland: Lists, 1946 (Box 117, Folder 22)
      Microfilm reel#: 339
    - Poland: Lists, 1947-1948 (Box 117, Folder 23)
    - Reports, 1948-1956 (Box 117, Folder 24)
    - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1954-1955 (Box 117, Folder 25)
    - Student Aid Project, 1947-1948 (Box 117, Folder 26)
    - Sweden, 1948-1952 (Box 117, Folder 27)
    - Toronto, 1947-1948 (Box 117, Folder 28)
    - Toronto, 1949-1953 (Box 117, Folder 29)
    - Washington, DC, 1956 (Box 117, Folder 30)
    - Workmen's Circle Branches 25 & 25B, 1947-1951 (Box 117, Folder 31)
    - Workmen's Circle Schools, 1954-1956 (Box 117, Folder 32)
  - Subseries IV:D: Child Adoption Case Files
    (Original files stored in JLC, Boxes Add.1-Add.13; consult staff for access.)
    - Adoption Case File Cards
      - Abrachoff-Bialo, L (Box 551)
      - Bialo, M-Chmielnicki (Box 552)
      - Chonowski-Fagadan (Box 553)
      - Faierman-Garcia Llaneza (Box 554)
      - Garde-Gutgisser (NOTE: Gutgisser file is out of alphabetical order) (Box 555)
      - Gurkow-Kameniecka (Box 556)
      - Kamerfuchs-Kysman (Box 557)
      - Lachtiger-Mantel (Box 558)
      - Marchewka-Perez Pasaro (Box 559)
      - Perk-Ryza (Box 560)
      - Sabocka-Szyndler (Box 561)
      - Tabacznik-Wengel (Box 562)
      - Wichnes-Zysman (Box 563)
    - Adoption Case File Microfilm Reels
      - Abraszkow, Henry to Baruch, Maurice, undated (Reel 340)
      - Baruch, Simone to Bialo, Jankiel, undated (Reel 341)
      - Birman, Mirca to Caisman, Elaine, undated (Reel 342)
      - Calkowicz, Nadzieja to Cybula, Theresa, undated (Reel 343)
      - Cygiel, Bela to Eichenbaum, Eta, undated (Reel 344)
      - Eidelberg, Aharon to Filc, Lena, undated (Reel 345)
      - Fingerman, Bernadette to Galanski, Majer, undated (Reel 346)
      - Galantina, Isabella to Goldberg, Rafael, undated (Reel 347)
      - Goldberg, Solomon to Grzybowska, Krajndel, undated (Reel 348)
      - Grzywak, Albert and Claudine to Horer, Suzanne, undated (Reel 349)
      - Horn, Feivel to Kagan, Lucien, undated (Reel 350)
      - Kagonowicz, Abram to Korek, Henriette, undated (Reel 351)
      - Korek, Leon to Kutas-Lapinowski, Cesia, undated (Reel 352)
      - Kutas-Lapinowski, Regina to Libermensch, Denise, undated (Reel 353)
      - Libersztajn, Simon to Martinelli, Giulia, undated (Reel 354)
      - Mascaretti, Luciana to Nomberg, Heniek, undated (Reel 355)
      - Novik, Marcel to Pesselman, Helene, undated (Reel 356)